I just built the SQL database agent with
my new AI data science team and I want
to show share how to do that in this
video okay so it's really easy it's
actually astonishingly easy to start
taking my AI agents that I'm building in
this AI data science team and
integrating them into this app so let's
check this app out so this is what it
does it basically keeps a history of it
Con connects up to a database so you can
connect it to like any database that you
want I'm going to show you how to do
that in this video you enter your a API
key for open AI you pick a model if you
want GPT 40 mini or 40 and what you're
going to do is go down through and we
can start asking questions about this
database we can start generating SQL
queries it'll produce data frames and
tables it'll
aggregate things like this one aggregate
sales for each territory and it produces
this complex SQL query something that
would personally take me a while to type
up and then it generates the result so
this is the the result after you execute
that query on your database all right so
this is what we're going to build today
it's part of my new AI data science team
so I'm going to link put a link to this
in the notes check this GitHub repo out
please do me a favor start it it
actually helps me it helps you find and
stay in touch with the changes but it
also helps me because it shows how
popular this this new package of data
science teams my new AI power data
science team is is getting but anyways
back to what we're trying to accomplish
here so I want to introduce you really
quick to this data science team that I'm
building it's an army of Agents
literally that you can pull off the
shelf so we're going to see the SQL
database agent in action today inside of
a web application okay so that's what we
saw over here underneath the hood one of
my agents is running okay I'll share how
to do that here in a second but first
let's just take a look at the GitHub
repo so this AI data science team it's
your army of AI agents that all do T
data science tasks the goal is to speed
up the stuff that you most L do so 10x
speed up of things like feature
engineering data cleaning data wrangling
SQL database queries machine learning
models all that stuff we're getting even
into multi-agents I have a I'm probably
going to end up building an app around
that one soon and then now what I'm
talking about here today is data science
apps okay so this is the first of many
data science apps that I'm going to
start building with this AI data science
team very very cool stuff all right so
over to the code what I'm going to be
doing here is I'm going to be sharing
how to use that SQL database agent that
I talked about in order to be able to
build this web application that
automates all the querying and does all
that that fun stuff so okay so the code
today I this is this comes from my AI
tips newsletter do me a favor join that
when you join the newsletter what I'm
doing is documenting my journey so as I
make all of these tutorials I'm
documenting every single one and when
you join you not only get access to the
code for this tutorial which is right
here this 010 SQL database agent but
there's more you get access to every
single one for free can't beat it um so
you get 10 10 tutorials currently and
more coming so you also get access to
the data that we're going to be running
I'm going to be using this North Wind
database today and that has a bunch of
tables it's it's pretty big database and
is great to simulate a company's Erp
system so enterprise resource planning
and we're going to build a seal database
agent on top of it all right so the code
that I'm working out of is this app.py
that's this streamlet file here okay and
what we're covering today is the SQL
database agent what it is so I already
kind of showed you what that was second
thing expose you to the new AI data
science team I also did that make sure
you start the GitHub repo and then the
third thing how to build the app that's
what we're going to do right now make
sure that you uh go to the project re
repo make sure you give it a GitHub a
star do me a favor Star right up here
right now pause the video star that
helps out big time the next thing that
you're going to do you're going to make
sure that you have the latest version of
the AI data science team installed you
just open up a terminal go terminal new
terminal and you'll pop that right in
here this line pip install with this get
string that's going to go right down
here and it's going to install the
software requirements if you want to
know all the requirements for this
particular app that I have that store
here in the requirements.txt file you
need your AI data science team make sure
you also have streamlet SQL Alchemy
pandas async IO I did actually set this
up for async which is awesome um Lang
chain Lang chain open AI because we're
going to be using open AI uh Lang graph
and open AI packages all right um then
this app is already set up for you to
basically use it from you know scratch
all right so whatever your database is
or you can even connect it to multiple
data bases you're going to put your a
label here and where that's going to pop
up is it's going to pop up right over
here your select database you see this
let me escape out of that yeah for some
reason the Apple thing keeps popping up
but anyways you're going to have a list
of databases okay so that's what's
that's what this is and then you're
going to add a query string okay and
that's going to be the string that's
going to connect you to your database if
you have a MySQL server or whatever else
you're going to put that in here and
you're going to connect up to it just
like the string that you would use to
connect up through SQL Alchemy all right
the model list because I have this
already all set up for o Open AI I'm
using their models so GPT 40 mini and
GPT 40 are your two options where those
will populate is once you put an API key
in this will pop up down here and you
can choose your model but you have to
have a an API key and you're going to PO
paste that in here so make sure you go
to open AI get an API key from them and
then you're going to paste that in here
and then what you'll be able to do is
start running that okay the rest is kind
of you know basic stuff for building
streamlet apps so you're going to
include a title of your app so my title
is your SQL database agent I have a mark
down here that tells you a little bit
about what this agent does so that's
this piece here we've got a little
expander here which gives you some
sample questions so when you open this
um this will be shut but you can just
click on it open it and then you got
your sample questions here um and then
sidebar is going to be these items over
here so that that's what's going to
populate your database options this St
sidebar select box is going to be select
your database we're going to store that
in the session state
and then also create a connection that
connection object will be used when we
create the seq agent this is the open AI
logic that makes sure that you've got a
valid API key before we proceed and then
if you do have an open AI API key in
there then this stuff will appear down
here where you can actually select the
model all right next part is the
streamlet app so this is the most
complicated part we've got a streamlet
chat history that's what populates all
of this stuff here so the streamlet chat
history
and then you've got a little indicator
here or a little session state where
we're going to add in session State data
frames and we're going to keep track of
those in our history so because we're
going to be producing these data frames
here we need to store those somewhere so
we're going to keep track as the user
interacts with our application we need
to store those and make sure that
they're persistent as they add new
questions like for example down here if
I add another question you know
aggregate the sales by month for each
territory pop that in down
here what we don't don't want to have
happen is all of the previous history
get deleted or especially these these
data frames okay so that's what this is
doing it's tracking each one of these
given each data frame an ID and so on
okay so you see there I've got month now
territory this is a completely new query
and you can see here that it saves the
all of the previous history okay so
that's what we're doing with this
display chat history and keeping track
of these data frames and stuff all right
here is the key thing it's one line of
code all we're doing is we're creating a
SQL database agent we're giving it the
llm model a connection calling it end
samples one to minimize the number of
samples that are that are going to be
going to our query we're going to say
log false because we don't want to
actually log any of the pipeline
functions that would be produced by this
SQL database agent when it makes the
queries and we're also going to bypass
one of the key steps which is a
recommendation step just to speed up our
process of building queries okay this
function here
this async defa might look a little
weird if you've ever done asynchronous
programming before but basically what
this is going to do is it's going to
invoke our agent
asynchronously why is that important
because inside of applications if you
got multiple users pounding you know
llms and trying to like Ping your you
know ping ping your if it's your open AI
account and they're all trying to Ping
it at once what they would have to do is
wait sequentially for each one of those
llm calls to be complete this async does
what that does is it allows you to
asynchronously if you have multiple
users of your app at the same time call
those queries asyn asynchronously uh
very handy so whenever you're inside of
apps you always want to have async
functions okay and then this is the part
that actually processes the query so
what you're going to have is once the
user enters a question in and as long as
they have a path to their database
present what it's going to do is if they
have an open AI account that's been but
verified uh it's then going to move on
to this logic here so what we're
doing is we're going to process and as
asynchronously we're going to run that
handle question function which is this
thing here all it does is just creates
from our created SQL database agent it's
just going to invoke it with whatever
the user question is all right and it's
going to return the SQL agent dated with
you know as it processes the question
it's going to have methods in here that
we can call okay so we're going to call
those methods down here assuming that
there's no error and we we get the
asynchronous result back what we're
going to grab out is the SQL query code
from that agent and we're going to grab
out the data from that SQL query so once
the SQL query gets executed on the
database it returns a data frame and
that's we're going to just take those
two and we're going to pop it in so if
there's a response we're going to
produce the SQL query as marked down and
then what we're going to do here is add
the data data frame to our session State
data frames so we're going to add add
that up here so we can track it and then
we're also going to print out the
response here okay and that's what we're
doing that's all there is to this app so
the beautiful part is you can literally
take this application update it with
your database options it's all ready to
run on any database that you want to use
let's give it a test spin here I'll
refresh it and I'll show you that it's
working if I pop in my SQL or my API key
oops wrong API key here let me grab an
API key uh here I'll throw this one in
here see if this one works
and we're good okay so we can see what
tables exist in the
database boom pop that in here run that
we should see this thing running here if
I go back up here see the agent is
running
and it's literally reporting the out
output results right here okay very cool
so last thing I probably should have
mentioned this previously but this is
what you use to run the app so if I want
to run the app here let's do this say I
control C the app kill the kill this app
the app is no longer running I can see
here site can't be reached you just run
this line of code here so let's paste
that in streamlet run and it'll fire up
the app for you okay and there we go